Guide to the INDUSCO Inc. Records
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
INDUSCO Inc. Records
1938-1985.
Indusco, Inc.
93 linear ft (180 boxes, 30 oversize folders, 2 card file boxes, & 1 glass slide box).
Columbia University Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, New York, NY 10027.
4079544
Biographical Note
Industrial cooperatives were established in China in order to aid in industrial production during the Sino-Japanese War. The CIC (Chinese Industrial Cooperatives) had three main headquarters (in northwest, southwest, and southeast China) to form the basis for small cooperative industries throughout the country, which in 1946 numbered 1,700 but which in 1948 had decreased to fewer than 500.
Scope and Content
These files contain typewritten reports of sub-units to the partent organization; periodicals and other publications issued in Chinese by the three regional headquarters (the early ones are probably quite rare); publications in English by these headquarters and by American committees formed to aid in the movement; mounted photographs showing the work of the cooperatives and their leaders; albums of newspaper clippings on the movement, emanating from the U.S. and abroad; maps showing locations of cooperatives; pencil sketches and watercolors of cooperatives at work; and other material concerning this important organization which was largly responsible for China's ability to feed and clothe, and otherwise care for her people as well as to carry on a major war.
1985 ADDITION: Correspondence, memos, and printed materials of Hugh Deane, including files on the revival of the CIC in the 1980s.
Arrangement
Selected materials cataloged; remainder arranged.
Subjects
China Aid Council.; Chinese Industrial Cooperatives.; United China Relief (U.S.); United Service to China.; Alley, Rewi, 1897-1987.; Zhou, Enlai, 1898-1976.; Zhu, De, 1886-1976.; Deane, Hugh.; Mao, Zedong, 1893-1976.; Song, Qingling, 1893-1981.; Dong, Biwu, 1886-1975.; China--Commerce--20th century.; China--Development--20th century.; China--Economic conditions.; China--Economic conditions--20th century.; China--Economic policy.; China--History--20th century.; China--Photographs--20th century.; Chongqing (China)--Economic conditions.; Cooperative societies--China--20th century.; Corporations, Nonprofit--United States--20th century.; Industrial mobilization--China.; Industrialization.; Reconstruction (1939-1951)--China.; Sino-Japanese War, 1937-1945--Economic aspects.; World War, 1939-1945--China.; World War, 1939-1945--Civilian relief--China.; World War, 1939-1945--Economic aspects--China.; World War, 1939-1945--War work--China.; Industries--China.; Rural industries--China.; Albums.; Articles.; Bibliographies.; Contracts.; Drawings.; Financial records.; Indexes.; Maps.; Minutes.; Newsletters.; Notebooks.; Photographs.; Photonegatives.; Poems.; Posters.; Press releases.; Reports.; Scrapbooks.; Slides.; Sketches.; Watercolor drawings.
Acquisition
1952 M-1952 Pruitt, Ida Gift
Gift of Miss Ida Pruitt, 1952-1956 & 1974.
Transferred from the East Asian Library, 1966, 1981 (negative files), & 1983 (slides).
Gift of Hugh Deane, 1985.
Elizabeth Schiffman Files: gift of Dr. Jessica Schiffman
- Cataloged Correspondence
  These files are arranged alphabetically by correspondent. To request cataloged correspondence, request the files by name of the correspondent.
  - Chou En-lai
  - Chu Teh
  - Li, Fu-chfin (see Mao Tse-tung)
  - Mao Tse-tung
  - Sun Soon Ching Ling (Mine. Sun Yat-sen)
  - Tung Pi-wu
- Series I: Chinese Industrial Cooperatives (CIC), 1938-1947
  - Subseries I.A: CIC Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Photographs
    - Sub-subseries I.A.1: CIC Correspondence
      - Lists of letters from China, by date of receipt at Indusco, N.Y., November 1946-December 1948, (8 folders) (Box 1)
      - Lists of letters from China, by date of receipt at Indusco, N.Y., January 1949-April 1950, (2 folders) (Box 2)
      - Extracts of mail from China, mostly taken from correspondence of Rewi Alley (some indexes), 1938-1944, (6 folders) (Box 2)
      - Alexander, John, 1941-1943 (Box 3)
      - Alley, Rewi
        (See also I.A.3, I.A.4, I.B.I Bailie Schools--Shantan)
        - 1938-June 1942, (21 folders) (Box 3)
        - 1942 July -1943, (20 folders) (Box 4)
        - 1944, (12 folders) (Box 5)
        - 1945, (13 folders) (Box 6)
        - 1946, (12 folders) (Box 7)
        - 1947, (12 folders) (Box 8)
        - 1948, (12 folders) (Box 9)
        - 1949-19454, (13 folders) (Box 10)
      - An Fan-chih 1949-Birdsley, Joan 1946-1947 (Box 11)
      - Braid, Andrew 1943-1947-Carlson, Evans F. 1939-1947 (Box 12)
      - Carpenter, J. Henry 1942-1943-Chao Shu-I 1940-1947 (Box 13)
      - Chen, Byron 1939-1946-Curwen, Anthony 1948-1949 (Box 14)
      - Dean, Sam 1945-Fisher, Weithy Honsinger 1947 (Box 15)
      - Fitch, George 1941-1946-Goullart, Peter 1941-1951 (Box 16)
      - Haas, Lily 1942-Herman, Theodore 1938-1941 (Box 17)
      - Herman 1942-1951-Hicks, Victor 1944-1946 (Box 18)
      - Higgins, Judson 1946-Huang, W. W. (Wen-wei) (Box 19)
      - Illsley, Walter 1946-1952-Liang Yu-chao 1948 (Box 20)
      - Lin, Dr. Robert 1939-1940-Meng Yiing-chfien 1940-1949 (Box 21)
      - Ming, Mavis 1942-1947-Pruitt, Ida, 1938 (Box 22)
        (See also: I.A.3, I.A.3, II.A.1)
      - Pruitt, Ida (Box 23)
        - 1939 (Box 23)
        - 1940-1942 (Box 24)
        - 1942-1944 (Box 25)
        - 1945-1947 (Box 26)
        - 1947-1955-Smith, Walter, 1946-1950 (Box 27)
      - Smythe, Lewis S. C. (Box 28)
        (See also I.A.3)
        - 1939-1943 (Box 28)
        - 1944-1945 (Box 29)
        - 1946-1952-Snow, Edgar, 1938-1945 (Box 30)
      - Snow, Helen Foster (Nym Wales) 1938-1947-Sweet, Lenning, 1944-1945 (Box 31)
      - Tan, J. M. 1942-1950-Townsend, Peter, 1942-1945 (Box 32)
      - Townsend 1946-1949-Turner, Margaret, 1948 (Box 33)
      - Wang, Anna 1938-Yip, Kenneth 1939 (Box 34)
    - Sub-subseries I.A.2: Cablegrams and Telegrams, 1941-1948
      - Cablegrams and Telegrams, 1941-1948 (Box 35)
    - Sub-subseries I.A.3: CIC Manuscripts, Printed Articles, and Pamphlets
      (pamphlets arranges alphabetically by author. See also V no 1)
      - Alley, Rewi (Box 36)
        - Articles and notes on CIC and cooperation, 1939-1950 (Box 36)
        - Articles, notes, and reports on CIC and Shantan Bailie School; poems by rewi Alley, typescript, 1938-1953 (Box 37)
        - Published Reports and Books (Box 38)
      - Armstrong, John Paul, 1948-Hogg, George (Box 39)
        (for George Hogg, see also I.A.1)
        - George Hogg--Articles on CIC and Cooperation, 1940-1944 (Box 39)
        - George Hogg--Articles and notes on Bailie Schools; printed articles; resume of work, 1940-1945 (Box 40)
      - Lyman John R., 1943 (Box 40)
        (see alsoI.A.1)
      - Mei, Y.P., 1941-Pruitt, Ida, 1939-1948 (Box 41)
      - Reisner, John H. 1939-Snow, Helen Foster 1939-1943 (Box 42)
      - Stevens, W. Mackenzie 1936-1943-Wells, Henry. W. 1950 (Box 43)
    - Sub-subseries I.A.4: CIC Biographical Materials, with Photographs
      - Alley, Michael (Rewi’s adopted son)-Alley, Rewi (Box 44)
      - An Fan-chih-Lyman, John R. (Box 45)
      - Mao Tse-tung 1948-Yung, K. S. (Box 46)
  - Subseries I.B: Subject Files, Printed Matters, and Photographs of Activities
    - Sub-subseries I.B.1: Subject and Organization Files
      - Indexes to materials ca. 1942 (Box 47)
      - AACIC (Association for the Advancement of CIC) 1943-1945-Army Goods, 1940-1944 (Box 47)
      - Bailie Schools
        - Appeals, 1944-Lanchow (Kansu) Bailie School, 1942-1947 (Box 48)
        - Shantan ([Sandan], Kansu) Bailie School (Box 49)
          - 1949 study by Yang Hsin-pao for FAO-Geological Drawings, 1945-1949 (Box 49)
          - Indusco mimeographed materials on Shantan and Lanchow Bailie Schools, 1944-1949 (Box 50)
          - Serials, 1946-1950, (2 folders) (Box 50)
        - Yunnan: Kunming Proposal, 1945 (Box 51)
      - Bibliographies of materials on CIC and on cooperation in China, 1940-1947 -- Exchange rate, 1944-1948 (Box 52)
      - Farmers Bank of China 1941 Human interest stories, 1939-1945 (Box 53)
      - Indusco Office for Supplies of Allied Military Services, 1943-1944-International Committee (IC) (Box 54)
        - International Committee
          - "Announcement" 1939-Finances 1942-1949 (Box 54)
          - Financial Statements, 1938-1947 (Box 55)
          - Financial Statements, 1948-1949 (Box 56)
          - Meeting Minutes
            - General Meetings, 1939-1951 (Box 56)
            - Annual Meeting 1945-1948-Executive Committee Meetings, 1943-1949 (Box 57)
            - Minutes of Joint Executive Committee Meetings 1946-1948-Minutes of JEC Projects Sub-committee, 1947 (Box 58)
        - Needs and Requests from China, 1941-1942 (Box 58)
        - Overseas promotion (notably Britain, Canada, postwar Japan, New Zealand, the Philippines), 1939-1951 (Box 59)
        - Peking Peace Conference, with photographs and news clippings, 1952-Refugees, 1943-1943 (Box 60)
        - Regions of GIG work (Box 61)
          - Regional analyses, 1941-1944 (Box 61)
          - General Data, 1941-1948 (Box 61)
          - Regional Areas of Work
            - Border Regions, 1939-1949 (Box 61)
            - Northwest Headquarters area (NWHQ) (Box 62)
              - Geographical file--sites of work activity 1939-1952 (Box 62)
              - Subject File (Box 63)
                - Conferences and Discussions, 1945-1946 (Box 63)
                - Reports, 1939-1946 (Box 63)
                - Serials, 1939-1945 (Box 64)
                - Women’s Work, 1939-1945 (Box 64)
            - Southeast Headquarters area (SEHQ) (Box 65)
              - Geographical File, 1939-1949 (Box 65)
              - Subject File
                - Articles on SEHQ, 1939-1949 (Box 65)
                - Reports--General, 1938-1939 (Box 65)
                - Reports--General, 1940-1947 (Box 66)
                - Technical Data, 1939-1947 (Box 66)
            - Southwest Headquarters area (SWHQ) 1939-1949 (Box 67)
            - Others (Hopei), 1947-1948 (Box 67)
        - Relief, Politics and problems of, 1938-1939 -- Rural Industry in China, 1942-1945 (Box 68)
        - Serials, National (CIC): Published in Chungking, Hongkong, and Shanghai, 1939-1950 (Box 69)
          (for non-CIC serials see I.B.3 Serials)
      - Shanghai Promotion Committee, 1939-YMCA, 1942 (Box 70)
    - Sub-subseries I.B.2: CIC Newspaper Clippings
      (See also V, no. 2)
      - Folders of clippings from Hongkong, Shanghai, the Philippines, and the United States, 1939-1941 1945-1948 (Box 71)
      - Binder of clippings from Hongkong, Shanghai, the Philippines and Hawaii, 1939-1941 (Box 72)
    - Sub-subseries I.B.3: CIC Printed Material and Serials
      - China Defense League, 1941-1943 (Box 74)
      - Hongkong Promotion Committee
        - Announcements, leaflets, pamphlets (many loose items) (Box 74)
        - Serials, duplicate copies of Indusco News and "News Release." (Box 75)
          (for publication details see I.B.1 Serials--Hongkong Promotion Committee)
      - Indusco, Inc. announcements, leaflets, pamphlets-Pamphlets, miscellaneous (Box 76)
      - Serials (Non-CIC) -- Unclassified Material (Box 77)
    - Sub-subseries I.B.4: CIC Photographs of Activities
      (see also V nos 4.b and 4.c)
      - Index of photographs-Bailie Schools: (Box 78)
        - Chengtu Bailie School-Shantan Bailie School (Box 78)
        - Shantan Bailie School
          - Arts and Drama-Electrical Division (Box 78)
          - Farm Division-Recreation and Hiking (Box 79)
          - Staff (Foreign and Chinese) -- Transport Division (Box 80)
        - Shuangshihpu (Shensi) Bailie School-Southeast Headquarters Bailie School (Box 81)
        - Unclassified Photographs and Negatives (Box 82)
          (largely of Shantan Bailie School)
      - Blanket-making-Exhibits (Chungking and U.S.) (Box 83)
      - Food-making-Machinery and machine shops (Box 84)
      - Matches-Regions of CIC (Box 85)
        - Border Regions (Box 85)
        - Northwest Headquarters area-Southeast Headquarters area (Box 86)
        - Southwest Headquarters area -- (Box 87)
      - Textiles
        - Ancient methods -- Reeling (Box 87)
        - Silk-Yarn preparation -- (Box 88)
      - Women (Box 88)
- Series II: INDUSCO, Inc.: U.S. Materials, 1939-1952
  - Series II.A: Correspondence and Photographs of Persons
    - Series II.A.1 Important Correspondence
      - Addis, Dr. Thomas (Stanford Univ. School of Medicine), 1946-1947 -- Crow, Carl (New York author and businessman), 1942 (Box 89)
      - Currie, Lauchlin (Wash., D.C., White House Adviser, Foreign economic Administration), 1942-1945 -- Freyn, Hubert (New York, China News Service), 1942 (Box 90)
      - Gamble, Sidney B. (N.Y., China Famine Relief, U.S.A.), 1940-1941-Hooker, Mrs. Edward (L.A., LOS Angeles-Hollywood Indusco Committee), 1941 (Box 91)
      - Hsia, C.L. (N.Y., Chinese News Service), 1940-1945-Kohlberg, Alfred (N.Y., Textile importer, later initiator of charges of communist leanings against I.P.R. and Owen Lattimore), 1943 (Box 92)
      - Lang, Olga (Boston and N.Y.), 1939-1942-Liu Liang-mo (N.Y., Chinese People's Chorus, speaker) 1942 1945 (Box 93)
      - Lobenstein, Edwin C. (N.Y., China Medical Board) 1940-1941-Orcahrd, John, 1939 (Box 94)
      - Peffer, Nathaniel (N.Y., Columbia University) 1940-1942-Pruitt, Ida (N.Y., Indusco, Inc.) 1941-1942 (Box 95)
      - Rauschenbush, Carl (N.Y., NYU, Indusco Executive Board), 1941-1943-Swisher, Earl (Boulder, Univ, of Colorado) 1940-1942 (Box 96)
      - Taylor, Mr. and Mrs. George (Seattle, Univ. of Wash.), 1940-1942-Warbasse, James P. (N.Y., President, The Cooperative League of the United States of America), 1940 (Box 97)
      - Welles, Sunner (Wash., D.C., Acting Secretary of State), 1942-Yu Tsime-chi (N.Y., Chinese Consul-General) 1940-1941 (Box 98)
    - Sub-subseries II.A.2: INDUSCO Routine and Fund-Raising Correspondence
      - 1940-1942 September 1942
        - A-E (Box 99)
          (missing, withdrawn by Indusco Office to make room for later materials)
        - F-G (Box 99)
        - H-J (Box 100)
        - K-L (Box 101)
        - M (Box 102)
        - N-P (Box 103)
        - Q-Se (Box 104)
        - Sh-T (Box 105)
        - U-Y (Box 106)
      - 1942 October -- 1944
        (section b. is less extensive than section a. due to a reduction in the number of private appeals for contributions made by Indusco following its 1942 contract with United China Relief.)
        - A-Ch (Box 107)
        - Ci-G (Box 108)
        - H-Z (Box 109)
      - 1945
        - A-C (Box 110)
        - D-J (Box 111)
        - K-Q (Box 112)
        - R-Z (Box 113)
      - 1946 (Box 114)
      - 1947-1949 (missing from files, discarded by Indusco) (Box 114)
      - 1950 -- 1952
        - A-L (Box 114)
          (missing except for miscellaneous files)
        - N-Z (Box 114)
    - Sub-subseries II.A.3: Photographs of Persons
      - Fenn, Charles -- Yarnell, Admiral Harry E. (Box 114)
      - Others (Box 114)
  - Subseries II.B: Indusco Subject and Organizations File
    - Americans, former residents of China, including missionaries, 1939-1949 -- Boards of Indusco (Box 115)
    - Boards of Indusco
      - Advisory Board, 1940-1951 -- Executive Board (later Board of Directors): lists of members, resolutions, and correspondence, 1940-1941 (Box 115)
      - Advisory Board, 1941-1950 (Box 116)
    - Branch Committees of Indusco, Inc. (Box 117)
      - Baltimore, MD -- Washington D.C. (Box 117)
    - China Aid Convention (November 1940), program and "Who's Who" of Participants -- Chinese Student Contracts, 1939-1945 (Box 118)
    - Church-related Groups (Box 119)
      - American Friends Service Committee 1939-1945 1950-1952 -- World Council of Churches, 1945 (Box 119)
    - Committees of Indusco, Inc.-Cooperatives, U.S. 1940-1945 1949 (Box 120)
    - Equipment sent to China (See II.C.2.b) -- Finances (Box 121)
    - Finances
      (See also the President’s War relief Control Board, IV.B Finances--Indusco and V. no. 7)
      - 1939-1940 (Box 121)
      - 122 (Box 121)
      - 1941-1944 (Box 121)
      - 123 (Box 121)
      - 1945-1947 (Box 121)
      - 124 (Box 121)
      - 1948-1952 (Box 121)
      - 125 (Box 121)
    - Gripsholm (ship), repatriation of Americans 1943 -- Indusco -- IC-UCR relationship, 1942 (Box 121)
    - Indusco-UCR/USC relationship, including contracts, 1940-1949 (Box 126)
    - Laborr U.S. 1940-1948-Library of Congress 1941 1946 (Box 127)
    - Mailings: letters sent out, mailing statistics, name lists, 1940-1943 1947-1950 (Box 128)
      (see also Publicity--form letters)
    - Maps of U.S. and Canada-Mimeographed materials: correspondence, reports, projects, articles, 1944-1945 (Box 129)
    - Mimeographed Materials, 1946-1948 (Box 130)
    - Mimeographed Materials, 1949-1950 (Box 131)
    - Minutes of Meetings
      - Corporation of Indusco, Inc. 1942-1947 1951-1952 -- Executive Board, 1940-1941 (Box 131)
      - Executive Board, 1942-1942 (Box 132)
      - Executive Board, 1946-1947 (Box 133)
      - Executive Board, 1947-1952 (Box 134)
      - Field Work Committee Minutes, 1942 (Box 135)
      - Policy, 1941 1947 (Box 135)
    - The President's War Relief Control Board (formerly the President’s Committee on War relief Agencies)%ne: correspondence with Indusco, Indusco Monthly and Quarterly Reports, Monthly Press Releases, 1942-1945 (Box 136)
    - Printing and stationery rates and samples-Publicity and Promotion Materials (Box 137)
    - Publicity and Promotion Materials
      - Anniversary of CIC congratulatory messages -- Films, including "A Nation Rebuilds," 1940-1946 (Box 137)
      - Form letters 1940-1952-News/press releases 1940-1946 (Box 138)
      - News/press releases (cont.)-Radio broadcasts 1940-1946 (Box 139)
      - Reports on publicity work 1941-1949- (Box 140)
    - Reports on U.S. promotion work 1940-1952 (Box 140)
    - Serials (Indusco, Inc.) (Box 141)
      - "Aims in Industries" 1942-Indusco Bulletin 1940-1952 (Box 141)
      - "Northwest Indusco News" 1942-1955 -- (Box 142)
    - Staff, Indusco Office: duties, resumes, salaries, insurance, union memberships, 1940-1944 (Box 142)
    - Staff, 1945-1950 -- (Box 143)
    - U.S. Government agencies (Box 143)
    - U.S. Government loans, Indusco proposals for 1940-1941-U.S. organizations concerned with China (Box 144)
      - China aid and study groups (local and special; national), 1939-1950 (Box 144)
      - Organizations to affect U.S. Government policies toward China -- Research and Discussion Groups -- (Box 145)
    - U.S. organizations for relief and reconstruction (not concerned primarily with China)
      - American Council of Voluntary Agencies for Foreign Service, Inc. New York, 1944-1946 (Box 145)
      - American Red Cross, Washington, D.C,- (Box 146)
    - YWCA
  - Subseries II.C: Techical Materials
    - Sub-subseries II.C.1: Technical Materials-Correspondence
      - Correspondence of David J. Leacock (Chairman, Technical Department, 1941-1944), 1941-Correspondence, Equipment Services Division (David King Rothstein, Director)A-F, 1946 August -1947 January (Box 147)
      - Equipment Services Division, G-Z (Box 148)
    - Sub-subseries II.C.2: Indusco Technical Materials--Subject Files
      - General (Box 149)
      - Equipment Corporation/Trust, 1944-1945-Mimeographed materials: correspondence, reports, China requests, minutes of meetings, 1943-1945 (Box 149)
      - Mimeographed Material, 1945-1946 (Box 150)
      - Technical data from China (Box 150)
      - Equipment and supplies for China 1940-1952 (Box 151)
        - Bills of lading 1946-1948-Esser project 1946 (Box 151)
        - Export license applications 1943-1945-Okinawa purchases (U.S. surplus property), 1946 (Box 152)
        - Purchases for China 1944-1948-Reports on materials sent to China: books, equipment, microfilm, 1940-1945 (Box 153)
        - Reports on Materials sent to China, 1946-1948 (Box 154)
        - Shipments to China, 195-1949 (Box 154)
          (Premier Shipping Co.)
        - Shipments to China, 1946-1947 (Box 155)
        - Suppliers, including invoices 1945-1949 (Box 155)
          (A-P)
        - Suppliers, including invoices 1945-1949 (Box 156)
          (S-W)
      - Technical Data, 1941-1944
        - Agriculture-Food products and processing (Box 156)
        - Fuels-Industrial equipment and processes (Box 157)
        - Industrial equipment and processes-Medical supplies (Box 158)
        - Metal -- Printing (Box 159)
        - Textiles (Box 160)
  - Subseries II.D: Miscellaneous
    - Description and critique of filing system at Indusco, by Gunther Stein, 1946 June (Box 160)
    - File cards to Indusco collection, loose, prepared by Howard Linton, East Asian Library, Columbia University; unfinished, 1966 (Box 160)
    - Filing Instructions, 1945 (Box 160)
- Series III: China Aid Council (CAC): China Materials, 1938-1947
  - Series III.A: Correspondence and Reports of Individuals
    - >Sub-subseries III.A.1: Correspondence
      - Bertram, James 1940-1941-Bethune, Norman 1938-1939 (Box 161)
      - Chen Han-seng 1941-Ma Hai-teh 1941-1945 (Box 161)
      - Mme Sun Yat-sen 1938-1944-Tung Pi-wu 1944 (Box 161)
    - Subseries III.A.2: CAC Mimeographed Letters and Reports from China
      - Nora Hsiung Chu, National Association for Refugee Children 1943-1945 T’ao Hsing-chih's Yu Ts'ai School,Chungking, 1943-1945 À Dr. and Mrs. Ernest Osbome 1946-1947 Mildred Price 1946 and Dr. W. Carson Ryan 1945-1946. (Box 162)
  - Subseries III.B: CAC Subject File
    - China Aid Council 1938-1949-International Peace Hospitals, Reports and data 1941-1944 (Box 163)
    - Subseries III.C: CAC Photographs of Persons and Activities (Box 163)
    - Canton Children's Center, one album
    - Yu Ts'ai School for Gifted Children of Tsao Hsing-chih (Box 163)
- Series IV: United China Relief (UCR)/ United Service to China (USC): U.S. Materials, 1940-1950
  - Subseries IV.A: Correspondence
    - Earnett, Eugene E. Chairman, Committee on Nominations 1942-1944-Garside, B.A. UCR/USC Vice Pres. and Secretary, 1940-1944 (Box 164)
    - 1945-1946 1950-Rhodes, Peter Publicity 1941 (Box 165)
    - Sweet, Lenning Director, Program Committee 1942-1946-Mrs. Lennig Sweet, 1941 (Box 166)
  - Subseries IV.A: Subject Files
    - Appeals, 1942-Program Committee, 1942-1946 (Box 167)
    - Finances (Box 168)
      - Allocations, 1941 (Box 168)
      - Indusco Budget, 1941-1948 (Box 168)
      - Indusco contributors list, monthly 1941-1942 1945 (Box 169)
    - Medicine and Public Health in China, conference (Box 169)
    - Minutes of Meetings (Box 170)
      - Agency Representatives meetings, 1945 (Box 170)
      - Committees
        - American Activities Committee, 1945 (Box 170)
        - Joint Committee of the Coordinating Committee, 1941 (Box 170)
        - Executive Staff Meeting, 1941 (Box 171)
        - Program Committee, 1942-1944 (Box 171)
        - Program Committee, 1945-1946 (Box 172)
        - Program Committee, 1947-1949 (Box 173)
        - Executive Committee (Executive Board), 1942-1945 (Box 173)
        - Executive Committee, 1946-1949 (Box 174)
    - Publicity, 1940-1945 (Box 174)
    - Reorganisation plan 1945-""Why every American should help China--Generously and Now", 1941 (Box 175)
- Series V: Oversized Items
  - Reprints, magazine articles, unpublished articles, 1939-1949 arranged and listed alphabetically by author. One loose-leaf scrapbook. (Box Flat Box)
    (See I.A,3, I.B.3)
  - Newspaper and magazine clippings on CIC, 1939-1948 chiefly from the Unites States, also from China, Hongkong, the Philippines, Canada, and Mexico. Two scrapbook volumes. (Box Flat Box)
    (See I.B.2, 1.3.3)